<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CLMBR</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello World</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="ok">Ok</string>
    <string name="continue_to_equipment">Continue to Equipment Selection</string>
    <string name="continue_to_start_date">Continue to Program Date Selection</string>
    <string name="accept_start_date">Accept Start Date</string>
    <string name="accept_end_date">Accept End Date</string>
    <string name="done">Done</string>
    <string name="reps">Reps: </string>
    <string name="sets">Sets: </string>
    <string name="equip">Equipment: </string>
    <string name="diff">Minimum Grade Range to be in Program: </string>
    <string name="rest">Rest: </string>
    <string name="type">Drill Type: </string>
    <string name="time">Time Allotted: </string>
    <string name="home">Cancel and Return to Home</string>
    <string name="create_program">Generate your Program</string>
    <string name="name_prompt">Name your training program...</string>
    <string name="name_error">Letters and spaces only, up to 12 characters</string>
    <string name="program_error">Once you create a program, it will appear here.</string>

    <string name="help_message_title">Help Message</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome!</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="exercise_database">View Exercises</string>
    <string name="load_program">Load Program </string>
    <string name="training_tips">Training Tips</string>
    <string name="remove_ads">Remove Ads</string>
    <string name="about_the_author">About the Author</string>
    <string name="new_program">Build New Program</string>

    <string name="program_segments">Program Segments</string>
    <string name="volume_only">Volume Only</string>
    <string name="strpow_only">Strength and Power Only</string>
    <string name="powend_only">Power Endurance Only</string>
    <string name="end_only">Route Endurance Only</string>
    <string name="full_programs">Complete Programs</string>
    <string name="bouldering_program">Bouldering Program</string>
    <string name="routes_program">Routes Program</string>

    <string name="filter_text">Filter Exercises:</string>

    <string-array name="program_types">
        <item>Volume Only</item>
        <item>Strength and Power Only</item>
        <item>Power Endurance Only</item>
        <item>Route Endurance Only</item>
        <item>Bouldering Program</item>
        <item>Routes Program</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="types_strings">
        <item>Strength</item>
        <item>Power</item>
        <item>Power Endurance</item>
        <item>Endurance</item>
        <item>Conditioning</item>
        <item>Volume</item>
        <item>All</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="PWR">PWR</string>
    <string name="STR">STR</string>
    <string name="POW">POW</string>
    <string name="VOL">VOL</string>
    <string name="ALL">ALL</string>
    <string name="END">END</string>
    <string name="CON">CON</string>
    <string name="PWREND">PWR-END</string>


    <string-array name="time_strings">
        <item>15 Minutes</item>
        <item>30 Minutes</item>
        <item>45 Minutes</item>
        <item>60 Minutes</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="days_of_week">
        <item>Sunday</item>
        <item>Monday</item>
        <item>Tuesday</item>
        <item>Wednesday</item>
        <item>Thursday</item>
        <item>Friday</item>
        <item>Saturday</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="Monday">Monday</string>
    <string name="Tuesday">Tuesday</string>
    <string name="Wednesday">Wednesday</string>
    <string name="Thursday">Thursday</string>
    <string name="Friday">Friday</string>
    <string name="Saturday">Saturday</string>
    <string name="Sunday">Sunday</string>

    <string name="days_select">Select the Days You Climb...</string>

    <string name="select_commitment">Select Commitment Level</string>

    <string-array name="commitment_levels">
        <item>Select Commitment Level...</item>
        <item>Moderate</item>
        <item>Dedicated</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="grades">
        <item>Select Current Grade Range...</item>
        <item>[5.10d or V0 and below]</item>
        <item>[5.11a to 5.11d] or [V1 to V3]</item>
        <item>[5.12a to 5.12d] or [V4 to V6]</item>
        <item>[5.13a to 5.13d] or [V7 to V9]</item>
        <item>[5.14a or V10 and above]</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sessions_per_week">
        <item>Select Current Sessions Per Week...</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="session_durations">
        <item>Select Typical Session Duration...</item>
        <item>1 hour</item>
        <item>1.5h hours</item>
        <item>2 hours</item>
        <item>2.5 hours</item>
        <item>3 hours</item>
        <item>3.5 hours</item>
        <item>4 hours</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="select_grade_range">Current Grade Range</string>
    <string name="select_sessions_per_week">Current Sessions Per Week</string>
    <string name="select_session_length">Typical Session Duration</string>
    <string name="select_equipment">Equipment You Have Access To</string>

    <string-array name="equipment">
        <item>Hangboard</item>
        <item>Campus Board</item>
        <item>Fill Wall</item>
        <item>Lead or Toprope</item>
        <item>Small Freeweights</item>
        <item>Pull Up Bar</item>
        <item>Kettle Bells</item>
        <item>Rings</item>
        <item>Moonboard</item>
        <item>Medicine Balls</item>
        <item>Therabands</item>
        <item>Angle-Adjustable Wall</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="review_segments">
        <item>Program Type: </item>
        <item>Hours Per Session: </item>
        <item>Days Per Week: </item>
        <item>Commitment Level: </item>
        <item>Grade Range: </item>
        <item>Program Start Date: </item>
        <item>Program End Date: </item>
        <item>Equipment Available: </item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- -
        This is an ad unit ID for a banner test ad. Replace with your own banner ad unit id.
        For more information, see https://support.google.com/admob/answer/3052638
    <!- -->
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/6300978111</string>

    <string name="bio_goes_here">bio goes here</string>

    <string name="about_the_author_text">My name is Miles Adamson. I started climbing when I was 6 years old,
        and am 25 now. From the age of 8 onwards, I competed in the Canadian climbing youth circuit.
        During this time I trained on a junior team at the University of Alberta climbing wall. I won Canadian Nationals
        3 times in lead. This was before youth climbers had a bouldering circuit, so I also competed in the adult bouldering
        competitions. At 21, I won Canadian Bouldering Nationals hosted in Edmonton, Alberta.\n\nFrom then on, I
        started to move away from competitions and more on to rock. I did my degree in electrical engineering at
        the British Columbia Institute of Technology. Being only an hour from Squamish, I went there constantly.
        Often I would bring my school work to the boulders, to work while I rested. In Squamish, I got into highball
        bouldering. During my degree I had climbed virtually every highball in Squamish, along with the majority of
        the classic lines. I had been to every area so many times that I started to explore more remote and obscure areas.
        I found many new highball lines, some of which are on the "Top 25 Highballs" list. The highball list
        I wrote for the 3rd edition of Squamish Bouldering.\n\nAfter my degree, I moved back to Edmonton to work as an Engineer.
        Edmonton is relatively close to Canmore, Alberta. There was Canada\'s hardest sport climb, Honour and Glory. At the time, it was graded 5.15a, and I
        began to project it. During that summer, Adam Ondra came to try to flash the route. He reached out to me for beta, and his
        attempt was featured in Reel Rock 13. I was very happy to have a brief cameo in the film, and later send the route myself. Adam
        had (appropriately) downgraded the route to 5.14d, but still it was my hardest redpoint to date. During the long hiked to the Colisseum,
        I had a ton of time to talk to Adam about training, projecting and climbing.\n\nMuch of what I learned is applied to this app,
        which I help you find useful in your journey!
    </string>

    <string name="tip_volume">Volume training is done at the start of any program. The goal is to ready your body for the amount of climbing you will be doing later.\n\nBy climbing at a high volume and low difficulty, you work towards climbing at both a high volume and high quality. Volume training is so straightforward that it lacks a bit in variety and interest. You simply do a ton of easy/moderate moves in a day, without getting pumped. If you fail on a climb during volume training, it should be due to fatigue. Avoid moves which are hard for you, and climbs sustained enough to get you pumped.</string>
    <string name="tip_volume_name">Volume Training</string>

    <string name="tip_power">Power defines how much momentum you can generate. It defines the hardest dynamic moves you can do. It is trained though explosive moves and drills.\n\nPower drills aim to help you generate momentum from positions which are difficult, and to catch/control the swing that results from them. Many powerful moves involve a foot-cut, but they don’t necessarily have to. The gains from training power, like strength, stay with you for a long time. This is why it is trained early in a training cycle, the gains will still be there when you peak. </string>
    <string name="tip_power_name">Power Training</string>

    <string name="tip_strength">Strength defines what static positions you are able to hold. It involves mostly hand strength and lock-off strength. Training strength is often done on a hangboard, pull up bar or on short boulders. Like during power drills, boulders should be 4 or less moves.\n\nBy training strength, you will be able to lock-off deeper, hold worse holds, and keep your feet on when otherwise you wouldn’t have been able to. Like power, the gains from strength training stay with you for a very long time. This is why when you take a break from climbing, it feels like you can climb similarly hard moves, but not nearly as many in a row or for as long in the day. This is why it is trained early in a program’s periodization; the gains will still be there for when you peak.</string>
    <string name="tip_strength_name">Strength Training</string>

    <string name="tip_powerEnd">Power endurance defines how many near max-difficulty moves you can do in a row. It also has to do with your ability to do a near max-difficulty move at the end of a longer boulder. The classic power endurance drill is the Four by Four.\n\nWhen training power endurance, your boulder problems length should be 8-12 moves. Ideally, they should be sustained or have the hardest moves near the end. The gains from power endurance stay for longer than endurance, but not as long as strength and power. Therefor you train it in the middle of a training cycle.</string>
    <string name="tip_powerEnd_name">Power Endurance Training</string>

    <string name="tip_endurance">Endurance defines how long it takes you to get pumped, and what percentage of your max-difficulty move actually get you pumped. With great endurance, you can do long routes with sustained sections, and actually recover when you rest.\n\nEndurance is trained by getting very pumped a bunch of times. Many people avoid it, finding the drills boring and monotonous. However, you will never be able to do a near max-difficulty move at the 12th bolt of a route without it. The gains from endurance are fast, and lost just as quickly. This is why if you take a break from routes, you get extremely pumped the first day back but then almost immediately start to feel better at it after a couple days. This is why it is trained last in a training program. If it were trained too early, the gains wouldn’t be there when you peak.</string>
    <string name="tip_endurance_name">Endurance Training</string>

    <string name="tip_fast_lead_laps">When training endurance on routes, many drills require you to do multiple laps. If you do this on lead and untie then tie in every lap, you will spend too much time on the ground resting. Also, tying in multiple times as fast as possible could lead to errors in your knot.\n\nThe fastest way to do lead laps allows you to climb multiple times without untying. After you lower from a climb, immediately go back into a start jug. Your belayer takes off their belay device, removes the knot from the end of the rope, and pulls the rope from the climber’s side. This makes the rope fall down from the top of the gym, so make sure to yell ROPE. The belayer then attaches again to be on belay, the climber checks their setup from their jug, and then climbs on lead again. Typically, top-rope walls aren’t steep enough for advanced climbers to train endurance on. So this method is key to getting the most possible out of your endurance training.</string>
    <string name="tip_fast_lead_laps_name">Fast Lead Laps - Don\'t Un-tie</string>

    <string name="tip_training_cycles">When you choose the end date of your program, this is the date you want to peak for. It could be for a competition, or a trip on rock outdoors.  The goal of the program is to space the different training periods in a way to maximize you gains for that specific date. This is usually done in cycles.\n\nA complete route climbing cycle looks like this:  volume, strength and power, power endurance, endurance, peak, rest. A bouldering program will do the same, except skip endurance. Competition seasons are actually designed to accommodate this. It is the reason that in a competition season, bouldering is first and routes are second. Some have tried to train in other patters, such as doing all phases simultaneously. This app does not support this strategy, even though it could be perfectly valid to.</string>
    <string name="tip_training_cycles_name">Training Cycles and Periodization</string>

    <string name="tip_session_length">Resting is absolutely key in training. It is extremely common for climbers to over-train and almost immediately injure themselves. Your training sessions should never be longer than three hours. Going to the gym twice for 2.5 hour sessions is MUCH more effective than a single 5 hour session. This is because with incredibly long sessions, you get so worn down that you have to take multiple rest days to properly recover.\n\nAs you get stringer and train more, it is ideal to increase the frequency that you train instead of increasing the session length.\n\nFor example, Adam Ondra never trains for more than three hours in a row. He does however train twice in a day. By resting just the afternoon, he is able to have a second meaningful session in the evening. He told me that doing the same drills over the course of a very long session led to him needing a rest day, effectively lowering the total hours of training he could output over a week. Even on trips he will train in the gym for maintenance. An interesting fact – the day he climbed Honour and Glory-14d second try, he ate supper and then still trained that evening. </string>
    <string name="tip_session_length_name">Session Length and Resting</string>

    <string name="tip_overtraining">It is incredibly important to listen to your body to avoid overtraining. Err on the side of caution whenever you are more tired than normal. Slight differences in your normal sleep schedule, stress and diet can leave you susceptible to injury. It is important to find the balance of training as hard as you can while always being confident you are safe from injury.\n\nSince this is such a personal thing, it is hard to give a simple way to determine. Losing a day of your training schedule is nothing in the context of an entire season. Injuries are! This is especially true because tired, low quality training days will be very effective anyways. </string>
    <string name="tip_overtraining_name">Overtraining</string>

    <string name="tip_minimum_grade">All exercises have a minimum grade range. This controls which drills can be put into which programs. For example, if you select the [10d or V0 and Below] grade range, you will not have drills with muscle-ups and front leavers included in your program.\n\nTo be clear, this is not necessarily the grade of routes or boulders you should be doing within the drill.\n\nIt is the minimum grade range to have the drill included in a program. There are plenty of drills where a 5.13 climber will be on a 5.12 or 5.11. </string>
    <string name="tip_minimum_grade_name">Minimum Grade for Exercises</string>

    <string name="tip_boulder_for_routes">Bouldering is essential for route climbing. Don’t let any 5.10 alpine climber tell you otherwise. When the hardest boulder you can do goes up, all moves below it in grade feel easier than before. If the hardest move you can possibly do is V3, how can you climb a V3 boulder at the end of a long route? What if every move is V3? You cannot possibly do fifty max-difficulty moves in a row. Now think, what if the hardest move you can do is V8 and you warm up on V3? By increasing your bouldering strength, you will very directly become a better route climber too.</string>
    <string name="tip_boulder_for_routes_name">Bouldering for Route Climbing?</string>

    <string name="tip_warm_up_name">How to Warm Up to Avoid Flash-Pump and Injury</string>
    <string name="tip_warm_up">A proper warm up takes most people 45 minutes. It is good to then plan for a full hour, in order to accommodate for some lost time getting changed and saying hello to everyone at the gym. A typical warm up could look like this:\n\n1.	Get your heart rate up through skipping, running in place, cycling, or extremely easy boulders\n\n2.	Do any injury specific warm ups which a physio has recommended\n\n3.	Climb progressively harder boulders, avoiding pockets, crimps and shoulder-intensive moves\n\n4.	Rest briefly and then climb some boulders which are harder but still well under your limit. Ease into crimps and pockets at this time\n\n5.	Climb a short circuit, or a long boulder slowly. Get slightly pumped, but DO NOT get flash pumped\n\n6.	Rest until you are no longer pumped what so ever. This prevents a flash pump later\n\n7.	 Climb some boulders or individual moves near your redpoint limit. Just a couple, don’t tire yourself out\n\n8.	Climb a longer circuit which gets you fairly pumped. Stop if you are feeling flash pumped instead of a normal pump, and go back to step 6\n\n9.	Rest for around 10 minutes, keeping warm with either a jacket or light cardio if it is cold in the gym or outside\n\n10.	If you time this properly, 45 minutes to an hour after you start you should be able to attempt a very hard redpoint or onsight. You should not be getting flash pumped or feel too cold to pull as hard as you can. If you are, remember what you did for a warm up and attempt to adjust and improve for next time</string>

    <string name="tip_hangboard_form_name">Hangboard Injury Prevention</string>
    <string name="tip_hangboard_form">Posture on a hangboard is very important for preventing injuries. Avoid locking your elbows and allowing your shoulders to extend fully. Proper form has your shoulders back opposed to hunched, and elbows bent slightly opposed to locked.\n\nAdditionally, you should avoid full crimping. Half crimping is fine, where your thumb is touching your pointing finger but not wrapped over top. If you full crimp, your open-handed strength will not improve and your risk of pully injury increases.\n\nAvoid hangboarding if your finger joints feel achy or stiff. Doing so can very easily lead to injury. If you feel achy or stiff, you either need to warm up better, do your hangboard routine earlier in your training day, or sleep more. Avoid hangboarding the day after drinking alcohol at all costs.</string>

    <string name="tip_alcohol_name">Alcohol and its Effects on Training</string>
    <string name="tip_alcohol">Alcohol has been linked to both the magnitude of injuries and their timeline for recovery.  It is extremely important not to train the day after a night of drinking, even light drinking. If you do, your risk for tendon/muscle tears will increase drastically.\n\nAlcohol also inhibits how well you recover after a training session. If you drink after training, you will see decreases in muscle strength and recovery time. While certainly not as destructive as training after a night of drinking, drinking after training will increase the amount of time you have to rest before you can train again.\n\nFun fact – Alex Megos did not accept a send beer after his first ascent Fight Club - 5.15b, even though it was also near his birthday! He declined the free beer sitting right in front of him, and instead ate a carrot as a reward for his climb.</string>

    <string name="tip_metolius_name">Training Boards - Metolius Climbing</string>
    <string name="tip_metolius">The Metolius Climbing hangboard routines are from their training guide. They are listed with the following instructions:\n\n\"Begin and complete the task or tasks within the one minute intervals. Use the remaining time to rest. Hang a watch from the bottom of the board or mount a wall clock so that you can look straight at it while training.\"\n\nTheir hangboards can viewed online with the link below.</string>
    <string name="tip_metolius_link"><a href="https://www.metoliusclimbing.com/training-boards.html">https://www.metoliusclimbing.com/training-boards.html</a></string>

    <!-- -
        This is an ad unit ID for an interstitial test ad. Replace with your own interstitial ad unit id.
        For more information, see https://support.google.com/admob/answer/3052638
    <!- -->

    <string name="title_activity_remove_ads">Remove Ads</string>
    <string name="title_activity_training_tips">Training Tips</string>
    <string name="interstitial_ad_sample">Interstitial Ad Sample</string>
    <string name="start_level">Level 1</string>
    <string name="next_level">Next Level</string>
    <string name="interstitial_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/1033173712</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_type_duration">Program Type</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_grade_commitment">Commitment and Climbing Level</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_about_you">About You</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_type_select">Program Type</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_equipment">Equipment Available</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_details">Choose Start Date</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_end_date">Choose End Date</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_review">Review Program</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_the_author">About The Author</string>
    <string name="title_activity_exercises">Exercises</string>
    <string name="title_activity_load_program">Load Program</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_exercise">View Exercise</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_tip">View Tip</string>
    <string name="title_activity_build_new_program_root">Build New Program</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_program_by_date">View Program By Date</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_dates_exercises">View a Days Exercises</string>
</resources>
